<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UW Research Lab Devs</title><link>/</link><description></description><atom:link href="/feeds/maria-mckinley.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 22:55:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><item><title>Design Pattern Meetings</title><link>/patterns.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In February, we started something new. Each month we are going to have a meeting dedicated to a design pattern. We started with the Strategy Pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Strategy Pattern defines a family of algorithms, encapsulates each one, and makes them interchangeable. Strategy lets the algorithm vary independently from clients that use it. (Head First Design Patterns)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed a scenario in which this pattern would be useful, and then talked about how to implement it. One very good example came up for using the Strategy Pattern in science. Often one wants to do statistics, and to do statistics one often needs distributions. But you don't always use the same distributions with the same analysis, so it is useful to have the distributions not be part of your statistical tools, but rather as a separate interface (usually a class).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March, we will be discussing the Observer Pattern. Meeting will be Friday, March 13th, at 4pm. We are going to continue to have an additional meeting most months, which will be either one of our own speaking about their coding and research or someone we bring in to discuss a particular topic. Our next meeting is February 25th, and we will be hearing some more from Genome Sciences. Please join our mailing list to get details.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maria McKinley</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 22:55:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:,2015-02-12:patterns.html</guid><category>meetings</category></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>/first-post.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings! The group has now been live for a few months, and I thought I'd give an overview of meetings we have had so far. The mailing list went live in May of this year, and we had our first get-together in June. It was a fun time; we met at the Big Time and spent a couple of hours just hanging out and getting to know each other. We skipped July, and then started to get slightly more organized in August:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;date&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;speaker&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;topic&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;August 6th&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Maria Mckinley&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Video Games and Memory&lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;    
        &lt;td&gt;Septempber 17th&lt;/td&gt; 
        &lt;td&gt;Maria Mckinley&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Code Review&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;   
    &lt;tr&gt;    
        &lt;td&gt;October 22nd&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Thomas Kramer&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Constructing an OO framework for processing heterogeneous geospatial sensor data&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;   
    &lt;tr&gt;            
        &lt;td&gt;November 19th&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Tom Kolar&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt; Java Swing application used by Clinical Researchers to look at DNA Sequencing data&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;   
    &lt;tr&gt;    
        &lt;td&gt;December 10th&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;David Gordon&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;Code and controversy&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Maria McKinley</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:,2014-12-28:first-post.html</guid><category>meetings</category></item></channel></rss>